AKHIL MS

A motivated individual with 3 years of in-depth experience and knowledge in languages and development tools. Seeking a position in a growth-oriented company where I can leverage my expertise to contribute to the company's success while also embracing opportunities for personal and professional growth.



akhilakhi7025@gmail.com

MUTHIRENTHIKKAL VAKKADAPPURAM P.O, Palakkad, India

in linkedin.com/in/akhil-m-s-

facebook.com/msakhil.akhil.1

+91 7025436330

akhilshajimuthirenthikkal.000webhostapp.com/

twitter.com/akhilakhi7025

github.com/akhil70

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering in ECE DHANALAKSHMI SRINIVASAN COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING COIMBATURE

07/2017 - 04/2021 CGPA-8.45

Biology Science GVHSS KARAKURUSSI

06/2015 - 03/2017 92%

SSLC

GVHSS KARAKURUSSI

04/2015 100%

PROJECTS

Marketing Application

 Contributed to the development of a dynamic Marketing Software application, crafting the frontend using React JS and implementing the backend functionality using Node JS. Technologies used: React Js, Node Js, MySqL

Recruitment Software

- This recruitment software has separate logins for candidates and recruiters. Candidates can apply for jobs by uploading their resumes. Recruiters can post job openings, view applicants, and manage resumes. It uses AI to automatically extract details from resumes. Technologies used: React Js ,Node Js ,MySqL
- https://recruit.xilligence.com

Stock Management Software

 crafted a stock management system featuring purchase order and stock transfer modules. Using React, is and Node.js, we ensure a responsive and intuitive user interface. The backend is powered by Node.js, and Amazon DynamoDB serves as the database for efficient data management and scalability Technologies used: React Js, Node Js, Amazon DynamoDB

TagTree Software

- TagTree is a software that lets users claim and update their location and business details on Google and Google Business Profile. It also uses Al to automatically create and optimize ads for businesses, helping them reach more customers easily.
- https://www.tagtree.in

SKILLS



EXPERIENCE

Working as a full-stack Node js and React js Developer(both front end and backend developer)

Have developed applications using a full stack React js + Node js web development tool

Have designed and developed modular and reusable RESTful APIs and front end components

Have worked with a team and managed work using a centralised set of project management tools $\,$

Web development using version control and code-based management tools

WORK EXPERIENCE

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER XILLIGENCE TECHNOLOGIES PVT LTD Technopark Trivandrum (07/2024 - Present)

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER Your Vision Software Solutions LLP Technopark Trivandrum (02/2022 - 07/2024)